# **Alexandra Alfadel**

#### **FULL STACK SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

alexalfadel@gmail.com > <u>LinkedIn</u> > <u>Github</u> > <u>Portfolio</u> > SF Bay Area

Full Stack Software Engineer and former tech sales professional, recently completed a 1000-hour immersive coding bootcamp specializing in full-stack web development.

LANGUAGES: JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, SQL DATABASES

FRAMEWORKS: Express, React, Flask,

OTHER: Redux, Node.js, Render, AWS

DATABASES: SQLite3, PostgreSQL, MongoDB

**TOOLS**: Git, Sequelize, SQLAlchemy

## **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

Trello >> Python, Flask, Flask-WTF, SQL, SQLAlchemy, PostgreSQL, SQLite 3, JavaScript, React, Redux, CSS <a href="GitHub"><u>GitHub</u>><u>Live</u></a>

- Enacted back-end validations for Card feature using Flask-WTF to ensure the submission of valid card data entries to the postgreSQL database.
- Utilized SQLAlchemy to effectively structure the Card model while enforcing validations, and to minimize database
  querying to ensure time optimization for future scalability.
- Enhanced user interface by leveraging **React** and **Redux** to isolate reloads to necessary components by managing Card state, while reusing components for the most commonly used features.
- Used CSS to aesthetically style the landing page to highlight app capabilities which encourages user registration growth.

ArtBeat >> JavaScript, Express, Sequelize, PostgreSQL, SQLite3, React, Redux, CSS, AWS

GitHub > Live

- Implemented **AWS S3** api to ensure the security and availability of show images, while prioritizing user experience and long-term scalability.
- Deployed back-end server with the use of **Express** and **Express Middleware** to manage error handling, and create an intuitive api for future application additions.
- Managed the reliability of Show and Image features by implementing the reusability of React components to optimize
  user interface and experience.
- Leveraged Redux state management in combination with React to upgrade user interface by excluding unnecessary re-renders of unchanged components on Show Details and Artist profile page.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

Rippling >> Account Manager > San Francisco, CA

May 2022 - January 2023

- Managed 500-800 small business clients achieved 97% year-to-date quota attainment with an average contract value of \$7,000.
- Sold suite of ~20 HR and IT products oversaw full sales cycle for clients from prospecting to closing.

Yext >> Mid-Market Account Executive > San Francisco, CA

October 2021 - May 2022

- Managed full sales cycle for marketing technology targeting brands with revenues ranging from \$25M to \$500M, achieving 96% year-to-date quota attainment with an average contract value of \$30k.
- Emphasized relationship building to upsell current clients while exceeding sales targets.

Instawork >> Account Executive > San Francisco, CA

June 2021 - September 2021

- Achieved 125% year-to-date quota attainment by prospecting and building a robust pipeline.
- Provided training and enablement to new reps on sales processes, product knowledge, and technology usage while
  contributing to executing new product initiatives and improvements within a hyper-growth startup environment.

Paychex >> Channel Sales Rep > Peninsula Bay Area, CA

June 2019 - June 2021

- Exceeded quota attainment with 129% year-to-date in FY20 and 135% YTD in FY21; trained and mentored multiple teams, leading to top-ranking achievements including #1 Pre Rookie and #3 Pre Rookie.
- Curated and executed training to develop CPA channel business, resulting in significant team quarterly activity growth (298%) and revenue growth (186%).

### **EDUCATION**

APP ACADEMY >> Full Stack Web Development

**Completed February 2024** 

Rigorous 1,000 hour software development course specializing in JavaScript, Express, SQL, Sequelize, React with Reduct, Python, Flask, SQLAlchemy, Test-Driven Development (TDD), algorithms, design patterns, and programming best practices.